Boma: Hello?
Boma: Oh, okay.
Boma: I guess we have to equip it for…
Boma: Nest 2 minutes, so we can… Start a poll.
Chase Wright: Hello?
Boma: Hello?
Boma: So, am I audible?
Chase Wright: Yep, I hear you.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: Okay, I can't… we can start, right?
Chase Wright: I guess so, unless you want to give it a minute, I don't know.
Boma: Wow.
Boma: Okay, let me… I'll just share my screen.
Boma: Okay, I guess we can start. Is my… can you see my screen?
Boma: Oh…
Chase Wright: Yep.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: Hmm…
Chase Wright: It's a holiday in the US, so… Awesome.
Chase Wright: Alright, this is probably gonna be low attendance anyway.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Has this ever been high attendance?
Boma: Okay, so… oh.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I mean, we can just park.
Boma: 6, 7.
Chase Wright: Yeah, what's up?
Boma: So I said on this PR, it's 6-7, so, I mean… I knew, like…
Chase Wright: This one's not gonna go anywhere, this one's not gonna go anywhere until we… until we figure out the ET Simulate V1 stuff, and so,
Chase Wright: we had the issue open, and multiple people have responded to it. So… I just opened a new PR.
Chase Wright: to update the eSimulate V1.
Chase Wright: spec?
Chase Wright: So… I mean…
Chase Wright: that's gonna have to get reviewed, but I just opened it, so that's… that's not gonna happen in this call.
Chase Wright: But yeah, I mean, the… That PR's not gonna go in until we…
Chase Wright: We come to an agreement on th-this.
Chase Wright: So, like, I don't know, you could review this, If you want,
Chase Wright: it's gonna require, like, a PR to go Ethereum, to add slot number, and things like that, so…
Chase Wright: I, like, we're not gonna make any progress on this call, for this particular… PR.
Chase Wright: But, everyone does seem to be in basic agreement about what ET Simulate V1 is missing, and what we should add, so we're gonna add slot number, we're gonna fix the bow, and we're going to…
Chase Wright: Depreciate the transfer log.
Chase Wright: for Amsterdam blocks. That's basically what the new PR is. So…
Chase Wright: once we get, you know, some thumbs up on that, and we get a few PRs up, then… then the…
Chase Wright: the update to Amsterdam can progress, but I think right now it's just stuck, so…
Boma: Okay, sorry, sorry to, like, jump in. On our last call, we talked about, I think,
Boma: Barnabas, if I can remember, he suggested you getting, a merge access to, like, have, like, a separate,
Chase Wright: Yeah, I mean, so I did talk to Felix about that, and that's work in progress, so, like, we'll probably do that, but right now, the problem is everyone agreeing on the spec. It's not…
Chase Wright: implementation, so it's not… that's not the blocker, but yeah, that is… that is work in progress, so…
Boma: Okay.
Boma: I think we can also skip this, because it's simulate, right?
Chase Wright: Yeah, yeah, that's just the issue, which… yeah.
Chase Wright: Warm.
Boma: Okay, and then on 862… Yeah. I think this is, like, it…
Chase Wright: this is also Amsterdam work, and I've already given, like… I've given the thumbs up on it, I think it's fine, but we need to get the Amsterdam stuff in first, so…
Chase Wright: Amsterdam stuff needs to land first, and then this one can be rebased on top of it, and then…
Chase Wright: And then this one is… good, as far as I'm concerned? I don't know if anyone else has…
Boma: Yeah, it says…
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Chase Wright: So… so that… so this one's just, also, just pending Amsterdam update.
Boma: Okay, so, okay, it's 6 to… Pending. Okay.
Boma: And then, what about X55?
Chase Wright: Yeah, so this one… I think… Yeah, so this one… is… like…
Chase Wright: You're the only one that has actually commented on the log index thing, but I mean… I agree.
Chase Wright: with you. So, what I think needs to happen is I need to update this one so that logs index is actually,
Chase Wright: specified? Because right now, it's just… Spec-only check, so,
Chase Wright: So this one is… this one needs more work. I… I'm gonna…
Chase Wright: I'm gonna change the spec so that log index follows GoEthereum's, and then we'll have to get all the other client PRs up, and get them to agree.
Chase Wright: And then if everyone agrees, then this one will be okay. But…
Chase Wright: it's obviously gonna have to get rebased on Amsterdam, so whatever.
Boma: Yeah, so I actually, like, have to, like, take note of the PRs that
Boma: that Amsterdam is blocking, so that we.
Chase Wright: So this one, this one is not blocked on Amsterdam. However, if we update all the, like.
Chase Wright: If we update all the tests, then this one's gonna have to get updated.
Chase Wright: because Amsterdam does change some of the fields.
Boma: Yeah.
Chase Wright: So this one's not blocked on that, I just need to get the log index specified, and then get everyone to agree to that. And if that happens, then in theory, we could… we could merge it. I just don't think that's going to happen before
Chase Wright: the Amsterdam stuff, but if it does, fine, whatever, it doesn't matter. It's all gonna have to get regenerated anyway.
Boma: Okay, well, I… Is there anyone on the call that has, like, a review on this particular PR?
Chase Wright: On the what?
Boma: I mean, it's… since we have some clients in here, do they have, like.
Chase Wright: Yeah, so, I mean, Geth already does… Do you mind giving it?
Chase Wright: So, so, Marius…
Chase Wright: will be happy, because Get doesn't need a fix. Nethermind, Lucas, you're on the… you're on the call. I don't know if you have an opinion about the logs index. I think Nethermind…
Chase Wright: Doesn't emit them at all, currently.
Łukasz Rozmej: Log index in Call Tracer?
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Łukasz Rozmej: I don't remember.
Łukasz Rozmej: I don't care.
Chase Wright: Yeah, alright, cool.
Łukasz Rozmej: To be honest.
Chase Wright: Yeah, yeah, yeah, so we'll… so I think it's just Erigon and Reth that are gonna have to update their, log indexing, because they do it on a per transaction level, and I think…
Chase Wright: Most people want it on the block level, so that the log index matches what the log index is on the block, so we'll go with that.
Boma: Oh, okay, fine.
Boma: Okay.
Chase Wright: This one is an engine change, and I don't, like…
Boma: Yeah, yeah, so…
Chase Wright: That's…
Boma: Oh, okay, I think…
Chase Wright: It's already.
Boma: Yeah.
Chase Wright: Huh.
Chase Wright: So, this one, it's in draft because of a GoEthereum PR. Marius actually reviewed my PR and already approved it in GoEthereum, so…
Chase Wright: This is mostly just a spec clarification update, and the only client that is different is GetH, so once GetH
Chase Wright: merges the PR, then I can, update the Go Ethereum version, and then
Chase Wright: We can… we can merge this one.
Chase Wright: In theory.
Boma: Yeah, it's pretty simple.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: Thank you,
Boma: the, okay, yeah, I think…
Boma: I opened an issue for this, but most clients have already, like, agreed on some things, but I can't recall what…
Boma: the last conversation on NIDS was.
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Boma: witness.
Chase Wright: I mean, so the problem with this one is that I'm, like…
Chase Wright: The spec work is, like, in progress, but…
Chase Wright: All of the clients kind of disagree, and so this was my attempt at writing the spec, And…
Chase Wright: GoEthereum is not necessarily following the spec as I have written it.
Chase Wright: And so I opened a PR2Go ethereum.
Chase Wright: And… they closed it. So I don't…
Chase Wright: I don't know how to move this one forward. I don't know how to spec this.
Chase Wright: Because the people who are working on it.
Chase Wright: Or not working on the spec.
Chase Wright: I don't… I guess, I don't know. It's complicated.
Boma: Okay, so do… do any client team have anything or comments on what the specs should actually look like to…
Boma: Push this forward, because we've been having this since a very long time now, and it would be nice to…
Boma: how specified… Sorry, go on.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Yeah, the problem with this is, like, the…
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): the consumer of this API are ZKVMs, right?
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): M… we… I don't… I don't… I don't necessarily know if we need this after bells anymore, right?
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): We could just.
Boma: Yeah.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): the bell.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): So… It seems pretty weird to me to specify something.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Where the consumer changes quite significantly, and the producer changes quite significantly, and…
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): like, we had this implementation of Execution Witness, but we never really… and, like, the fork choice updated with Execution Witness.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Never really used that, so…
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): I don't know, it seems like so many things are in flux, too many things are in flux for us to probably.
Boma: So, in my last understanding is that, I think Jason from, the ZKVM implementers, he… he also left a comment on this. I was thinking that should be enough for clients into, like.
Boma: Know all… Have, like, A solid spike on what this should actually be.
Boma: Or is this something we can come back later, or… I'm not sure how…
Boma: If we are moving forward with it, or we are going to, like, pause it for a while, then come back to it later on.
Chase Wright: I mean, I think the problem is the people who are consuming it, and the people are not… like, they're…
Chase Wright: they're not engaging, right? So, like, I don't… I don't know what to…
Chase Wright: what to do. Like, we could just drop it, but dropping it is…
Chase Wright: then, like, all the client… the clients are different, right? So…
Chase Wright: Why are they different? And I don't… I don't have an answer to that question.
Chase Wright: And who cares? I also don't have an answer to that question.
Boma: So I'm not sure… there's a call on zkVM, I don't know if it's the right call. Is it okay to bring this up to the call, or…
Chase Wright: I mean, yeah, I guess so.
Boma: Okay.
Łukasz Rozmej: Are there tests for this endpoint already?
Boma: Sorry?
Chase Wright: Like, we don't have… tests…
Chase Wright: in, like, execution APIs, like, that's what this is… Trying to do.
Łukasz Rozmej: Because I remember on the ZK side, there were some test changes, and there were some API metals in those tests.
Łukasz Rozmej: which were related to ZKK and the witnesses exactly, so…
Łukasz Rozmej: I'm not sure if this is this endpoint or the other endpoint, but it would be good to take a look what's there.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I mean, fair enough, but, like, if you call the method against the various clients, they all return different things. So, even if there are tests, I don't know what they're testing.
Łukasz Rozmej: Yeah, I'm not sure if this is this one or other endpoint, but I know there were some tests.
Łukasz Rozmej: And it can be this way, that some clients might be, you know, some clients might have adopted, some clients might have left it untouched, etc. There's too many things going on, to be honest, too.
Łukasz Rozmej: Always be on top of everything, but yeah, I do know that there are some ZKK tests, ZKK-related tests in a z…
Łukasz Rozmej: some zK test suits that are related to JSON, RPC, and witnesses. I'm not sure of this one, exactly, but…
Łukasz Rozmej: That might be kind of… A way of speccing some parts of it.
Łukasz Rozmej: Looking what's in the tests, that's kind of…
Łukasz Rozmej: I don't know. I can try looking it up.
Boma: Sorry, the test you're talking about, is it the, spec test?
Łukasz Rozmej: Yeah, kind of. I haven't implemented it, I know what…
Łukasz Rozmej: Daniel and Ruben from our team, but yeah, we're working on it.
Boma: Okay.
Łukasz Rozmej: Some time ago, so that's why I have only vague recollection what was there.
Łukasz Rozmej: Hmm…
Boma: I guess we can come back to this, and I can also, like, get it…
Boma: To the thing they have recalled.
Boma: I'm not sure if this is the right call, actually, Bo.
Boma: Mmm, this has to do with Amsterdam.
Boma: Oh, okay.
Boma: This engine payload.
Boma: then it's… Basics…
Boma: Okay.
Chase Wright: Oh, yeah, so this one,
Chase Wright: This one is pending a GoEthereum PR.
Chase Wright: So, if you look at his initial…
Chase Wright: PR description. There's a GoEthereum PR.
Chase Wright: Linked for returning null for missing raw transactions.
Chase Wright: It's been up since June 26th, and…
Chase Wright: Felix assigned himself on June 30th, and it hasn't… it hasn't been reviewed. So…
Chase Wright: Like, we can't do anything with this unless… Kath?
Chase Wright: Reviews it, and has an opinion.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Mmm. We should… we should just add, like,
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Like, a comment that, yeah, this is blocking something, please.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): review it.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Like, it's… it's… it's not easy for us to…
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Distinguish as the guest team, to distinguish between
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): random PRs that, like, someone made, and…
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): just forgot about, and PRs that someone really wants to get in, and is, is,
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): is blocked by it. So if you could just add a… add a comment that, hey,
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): I don't know, we are blocked by this.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Or we would really like to get this in. Can you please take a look?
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): And then it pops up for us again, and we can prioritize it over other stuff.
Chase Wright: Yep, that's fun.
Boma: So, okay, this is… yeah.
Boma: Oh, okay. You bring me to it.
Boma: Thank you.
Boma: I think, 7, 9… Must beza, actually, from you.
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Chase Wright: So this is… this is just the PR that's removing that, unused…
Chase Wright: Random error code from the,
Chase Wright: From the block. So, we talked about this, error code negative 39001.
Chase Wright: Nobody's actually following it, except… Besu, I think?
Chase Wright: So… That was the blocker for the other PR.
Chase Wright: Because you, you brought it up, what about this error code? So…
Chase Wright: All I really need is some thumbs up and people to…
Chase Wright: say this is fine, and then we could merge this, and if we merge this, then that unblocks the other pull requests for GetHeaders by hash and GetHeader by BlockNumber.
Chase Wright: Yep.
Chase Wright: I don't know.
Boma: Yeah, since we have a client in here, that would be nice to get a thumbs up from them, but I'm not sure if this affects basically… is it that it affects them, or…
Boma: I don't know what they're called, but they look like.
Chase Wright: I mean, in theory.
Boma: Do we need them to specifically thumbs up to this also?
Chase Wright: I mean… the… The clients already do not match.
Chase Wright: Besu and Erigon… do not match… The other 4 clients.
Chase Wright: So, like… I don't know.
Boma: What I'm asking is, if these get matched, do they need to be aware of these changes? Maybe if it's something that would affect them, if this…
Chase Wright: So there's no test for it today that they would fail on.
Chase Wright: If the other PR gets…
Chase Wright: approved and merged, then they will start failing those tests, I think. Well, no, because error code is usually ignored anyway.
Chase Wright: I mean, yes, we should let them know.
Chase Wright: But… Does it affect them in any way? Probably not.
Boma: Okay, but since we have, Get and NetherMind, do we… can we get, like, a review from you on this? That would be great.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Yeah… sure.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Sounds good to me.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Like, I'm not in front of my laptop, so I cannot give it a thumbs up right now, but I will.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): I will try not to forget it.
Stavros Vlachakis: I single another man said we are fine.
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Boma: Okay, thank you.
Boma: Hold on.
Boma: And 7, 877… Okay, this is 7 dropped.
Chase Wright: So this is only in draft, because… Erigon?
Chase Wright: Has Erigon needs a fix?
Chase Wright: Which I did submit, but it's kind of a complicated fix for them, so…
Chase Wright: They are… but they seem willing to make the change?
Chase Wright: Besu needs to implement the methods, so… but I have PRs to every single client,
Chase Wright: I just need…
Chase Wright: Basically, to take this out of draft, I just need people to say, like, yes, we should specify this, and it should be part of the spec.
Chase Wright: That's… that's basically it. Like, these methods are mostly implemented.
Łukasz Rozmej: Why do we need it? Aren't they redundant?
Chase Wright: I mean, that is a… that is a question, potentially, for the original implementers.
Chase Wright: Because these methods already exist, they're in the clients, So, like…
Łukasz Rozmej: Okay, okay.
Chase Wright: Yeah, so, like, should we spec it, and make sure they all match? Or… We're not.
Boma: Yo.
Stavros Vlachakis: I would say.
Boma: I have, like… Sorry, sorry, go on, sorry.
Stavros Vlachakis: No, no, I just wanted to say, yeah, let's spec them.
Chase Wright: Yeah, okay. So, I mean, this is the spec, and each client needs, like, a small… a small fix, and there are… I opened draft PRs for all of them, just because I didn't want to bother the implementers with
Chase Wright: Until the spec was… Thumbs up, basically.
Chase Wright: Like, even Erigon has it, it's just under the Erigon namespace instead of the ETH namespace, so… like…
Chase Wright: It's a small, small, small change,
Chase Wright: But if everyone is on board, then, like, I just make all the PRs not draft and get everyone to agree.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: I guess… EL.
Boma: We can do that.
Boma: I didn't…
Boma: One last thing I did not put on the agenda, it's about the error code.
Boma: Are we still talking about that, or it's just gone?
Chase Wright: We… we did talk about the error code. The negative 39001, that was…
Boma: Not, not that one, the one with, Felix and, Sims and, Sina.
Chase Wright: Yeah, okay.
Chase Wright: -Oh.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: So, 875… I think this PR is…
Chase Wright: Yeah, I just need… I just need thumbs up. This… everyone already does this, so…
Chase Wright: ethrex is fixed, and everyone already does this. So, I just… That's neat.
Boma: Nethermind also gives… give a thumbs up.
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Łukasz Rozmej: I would say, if everyone already does this, don't even ask us, just… Enshrine it.
Łukasz Rozmej: Fair enough.
Chase Wright: Alright.
Boma: We can't get this merged, yeah?
Chase Wright: Yeah, sure, I'll do it after the call.
Boma: Okay?
Boma: Why?
Boma: What's open to my screen?
Boma: Okay.
Boma: Mmm, I think… this is also good to me. I don't see any much,
Boma: Big of a change here, or do you have any… Reservations on this.
Boma: Hello?
Chase Wright: Yeah, I don't… I don't… I assume that this is correct and fine?
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Wait.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): What is this?
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Clarify, few recipients, not Coinbase.
Boma: Can you see? Because I think.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): some part.
Boma: oof.
Chase Wright: This is part of block overrides, right?
Chase Wright: be a recipient.
Chase Wright: He's boss.
Chase Wright: So this is a clarification to ETH Simulate Payload.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Whoa…
Boma: I'm not sure…
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): This… it's correct, but it's, like, it's pretty unnecessary.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): It's… I would just merge it.
Boma: Yeah, it's just this,
Chase Wright: particularly.
Boma: Slowly clarification.
Chase Wright: Best kind of crush, right?
Chase Wright: That seems fine, I don't know.
Boma: Yeah, it looks… It's more of a clarification thing.
Chase Wright: Alright.
Chase Wright: If no one objects, I will… I will just merge it.
Chase Wright: Seems fine.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Yeah, dude.
Boma: And then, 872…
Boma: I double-booked on this… oh, okay.
Boma: And this, I don't really understand,
Chase Wright: So I think… I think this is just legacy behavior of some of the clients, so…
Chase Wright: You can pass input, And you can… and, like, data was the old way of passing it.
Chase Wright: And some of the clients still accept either.
Chase Wright: At least that's my interpretation of this.
Boma: Is it necessary? Like…
Chase Wright: I don't… I don't think it's necessary.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): No, I don't… I don't… no, I don't think that should be added to the… to the schema. This is, like, legacy behavior that should not be part of the schema.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Like, the schema should be forward-looking.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I agree with that, and I think that, like, clients honoring the old data key as input is just…
Chase Wright: Client-specific legacy behavior that We shouldn't specify.
Chase Wright: or encourage.
Chase Wright: At least, that's my take. Okay.
Łukasz Rozmej: specify one, if clients support aliasing, that's fine, but I wouldn't.
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Łukasz Rozmej: refine it.
Chase Wright: Alright, I'll leave a… I'll leave a comment and get the… Guy's… response?
Łukasz Rozmej: Close it.
Chase Wright: Just close it, alright.
Łukasz Rozmej: Move forward, you know.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Yeah, just…
Łukasz Rozmej: Brave.
Chase Wright: Alright.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Yeah.
Boma: I mean…
Łukasz Rozmej: Done!
Chase Wright: Good.
Boma: Then, this issue, GetLogs Improvement.
Boma: Although I did not really look at it, so I'm not sure what exactly.
Chase Wright: I did not look at this either.
Chase Wright: Oh, actually, well, okay, so… Part of the clarification
Chase Wright: of this is the ETH Get logs what it does for a future block.
Chase Wright: That was part of…
Chase Wright: this, but this has a lot of other weird issues that I don't know that we can even
Chase Wright: solve in RPC standards?
Boma: Yeah, but why is it saying that RPCs is not very efficient… inefficient in what way?
Chase Wright: Yeah, I don't know.
Łukasz Rozmej: So, looking at this, no built-in rework handling, huh.
Łukasz Rozmej: I'm not sure if we built it or not, but we… I think there is a re-handling, but it's only through ETH Subscribe?
Łukasz Rozmej: if I'm correct, you get that some logs you have gotten now have the removed flag?
Łukasz Rozmej: Right? I'm not sure if I'm hallucinating of… or this is… this is true, I haven't looked at that for so long.
Łukasz Rozmej: But I think so, that there is a rear handling in… 48 subscribe.
Łukasz Rozmej: You cannot really have easy error handling through just an endpoint, because you need to have some state to know what you send to the spear and what you haven't, so that's one thing.
Łukasz Rozmej: No consistent error on unexceeded ranges. That might be true, so that's, like, defining proper error codes.
Łukasz Rozmej: No pagination, that's…
Łukasz Rozmej: Kind of true, so it would… might be good to… to… but this would be kind of…
Łukasz Rozmej: new endpoint, probably, because I don't really see how you can easily add pagination here.
Łukasz Rozmej: That we would have to design.
Łukasz Rozmej: So, for example, because most clients or nodes have… maybe nodes, not clients, have limits on how many, data they will, send you.
Łukasz Rozmej: It would be good to have somehow…
Łukasz Rozmej: A way to re-request the same query, saying, oh, this was the last data you gave me, and please give me data from this point.
Łukasz Rozmej: On forward, right?
Łukasz Rozmej: So that's pagination here.
Łukasz Rozmej: Json RPC is not very efficient,
Łukasz Rozmej: there was a lot of, work on that, so both we and Gav have, specialized, and probably all other clients too, but…
Łukasz Rozmej: We have indexes that are specialized for…
Łukasz Rozmej: Efficiency, and efficiency is a broad word, because ET gauge GetLogs might get…
Łukasz Rozmej: There are different, very different use cases. For example, you can have a very narrow, let's say, query, so not much blocks, but a lot of logs, but you can also have a very long-range scan for queries. So, say.
Łukasz Rozmej: give me all logs on this from Genesis, right? And you have to, look up through…
Łukasz Rozmej: Millions of blocks.
Łukasz Rozmej: And indexes generally help with the second, second problem, not the first one, so… I would say it's efficient a lot of the times, actually, with those indexes. When fetching up to latest.
Łukasz Rozmej: You don't know what latest was, just… Yeah, that's somewhat fair criticism.
Łukasz Rozmej: But then… don't fetch up to latest?
Chase Wright: Yeah, I mean, the whole problem with latest is… has always existed in that…
Chase Wright: If you load balance, you never know what you're gonna get, unless every node is at the same block, which…
Chase Wright: not true on very fast networks a lot of time. And the… the solution to that is to use a block number, or use a… use a…
Łukasz Rozmej: Yeah, yeah, like… I get what you're saying.
Chase Wright: Cool.
Łukasz Rozmej: Yeah, so I don't think we can solve 5 easily.
Łukasz Rozmej: We could get… do something…
Łukasz Rozmej: new endpoint that potentially solves this, right? That's…
Łukasz Rozmej: it's similar to GetLogs, but have pagination, and it can respond what latest was on its query, right, for example?
Łukasz Rozmej: So we could do something, but we cannot really solve it in GetLogs directly without breaking the contract, so…
Łukasz Rozmej: Yeah, so those are my comments.
Boma: Okay, thank you.
Łukasz Rozmej: The rear car…
Boma: I'm not sure.
Łukasz Rozmej: Should be there. One is not true, I think, if you use ETH subscribe for logs. Then you have error handling… ERC handling, not error handling.
Łukasz Rozmej: Which… what you should be doing if you want that. Otherwise, I don't know, what do you want.
Łukasz Rozmej: You cannot have that on a stateless endpoint.
Boma: Sorry, would it be okay if you, like, make a comment on the issue?
Boma: Because I barely understand, the entire 5 points he listed.
Łukasz Rozmej: Yeah, sure, can you give me the link in the chat?
Boma: View.
Boma: Fun fact is, I'm not sure how to get the chat whenever I'm sharing my screen.
Łukasz Rozmej: Okay, let me try getting it…
Boma: It's 706.
Boma: Okay, thank you.
Boma: Oh, look at it.
Boma: Okay, then… we talked about Hive last two weeks, I guess, and then this…
Boma: We're supposed to go in.
Boma: I'm not sure what happened.
Chase Wright: I mean, currently, the only one who's reviewed this is LightClient, and he's not on the call, so I don't know…
Chase Wright: I don't know what his problem is with it.
Chase Wright: like, well, I kinda do, in that… It's a bunch of code.
Chase Wright: For an awkward situation.
Chase Wright: it… what I'm trying to do is…
Chase Wright: If we want to specify named tracers, then…
Chase Wright: The… the schema validation needs a way to know which schema to look at.
Chase Wright: Otherwise, they all fall through to the, like… Match… match anything, basically?
Chase Wright: So, like, this particular PR is not… required.
Chase Wright: But… what ends up happening is…
Chase Wright: If we try to create a specification for a named tracer.
Chase Wright: then they all basically fall back to being spec-only tests without this change. So, in Hive, the test would run, and it would return a result.
Chase Wright: And the result would fall through to a, like, match-any situation. And so, everyone's test would get a green checkmark, and it would say that it passed.
Chase Wright: Even though it… it should have been, not spec-only. It should have been deterministic.
Chase Wright: So that's the blocker in Hive with this. Like, we can still spec Call Tracer and other name tracers, but Hive, without this particular change, is just going to say everything is green, no matter what, basically.
Chase Wright: So, unfortunately, unless I can get Light Clients, or Felix, or someone else to review.
Chase Wright: or answer my questions about how we could… if anyone has another idea how to solve the problem, I'm all for it, but I don't…
Chase Wright: Don't know how to move forward.
Boma: Okay, do any client team have anything to say in regards to this?
Boma: Oh, I guess not. Okay. I'm not…
Boma: I don't really have an opinion on… in…
Boma: anything related to Hive, as I… Could barely understand.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I mean, it's just a messy solution, but it's also a messy problem, because… the open… like…
Chase Wright: the RPC standards… Schema parsing is… Confusing.
Boma: Okay, what about, is this something we need to…
Boma: if it's something the OpenRPC guide can help us, Patch.
Boma: It just has to be here.
Chase Wright: I think it has to be here, because here is where the evaluation is done in Hyde.
Boma: Determine.
Chase Wright: Determine if the client passes or not.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: So… I don't know, maybe we can ping, like, Klein or Felix if he's back, I'm not sure.
Boma: Or if anybody has any other comment on it, or a solution, that would be great.
Boma: Then, these are the PRs we are supposed to… March last week, I think.
Boma: Oh, this is a city-Amsterdam issue.
Chase Wright: Yeah, this… this one is… This one can't be merged until we finish.
Boma: Yeah.
Chase Wright: Mulet.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: You've already reviewed this. Any more comments?
Boma: Looks fine.
Chase Wright: No, I think… I think this can be merged unless anyone objects. It's just adding two tests for gas price and max for energy.
Łukasz Rozmej: If we're passing it, sure.
Chase Wright: I think so. I can… I can double check. I'll the primary.
Łukasz Rozmej: Again, like I said, if it's something that has zero,
Łukasz Rozmej: Zero actions from us, but don't even worry about it.
Łukasz Rozmej: Let's do it.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: And then our CHAID UVA should be… this one.
Łukasz Rozmej: What does that do? EIP…
Łukasz Rozmej: I'm not sure what this object is, but…
Chase Wright: Yeah, so you can pass an object. Instead of passing block number, and then the block number, or block hash, or the block hash, you can pass in an object, and that object
Chase Wright: has…
Chase Wright: basically what's right there in the very top of the description. It can have block hash, and then a block hash, and then it can do require canonical true or false.
Chase Wright: So, this already exists?
Chase Wright: And it's just adding tests for it, basically.
Łukasz Rozmej: Merge?
Łukasz Rozmej: Yeah. Admion already exists, and I… I agree.
Chase Wright: Yeah. I mean, light client reviewed it, asked a question, and then… Disappeared, so… That's why it's still pending.
Łukasz Rozmej: Again, if it exists, fine.
Chase Wright: Alright.
Boma: But it would be generally good to, like, get thumbs up from clients, so that it's…
Boma: we see, like, the full consensus about the PR.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Yeah, the problem is that, like, then we will never merge anything, because clients are just not looking at it.
Łukasz Rozmej: I don't have enough time to look at PRs in my repo.
Marius Van Der Wijden (M): Cheer.
Chase Wright: I mean, the blocker was that a client developer did look at it, added comments, And then…
Chase Wright: disappear. That… that's my problem.
Chase Wright: But, I'll take everyone on this call's review as good enough.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: I'm not exactly sure what this is.
Chase Wright: This is Stefan's, but, this is adding,
Chase Wright: Well, first, we have to define Call Tracer, because Call Tracer is not spec'd. So, MyPR is doing that, but MyPR is currently doing that for pre-Amsterdam.
Chase Wright: And now, we need to add the bowel stuff.
Chase Wright: And all the other Amsterdam stuff?
Chase Wright: here. So, all of the work Has been done?
Chase Wright: To… to do that?
Chase Wright: Except for, we need to generate Amsterdam Chain?
Chase Wright: So, this is basically just blocked on, we need to fix ET Simulate V1.
Stefan Starflinger: Fix where? In the current client branches, or…
Chase Wright: No, no, so Eat Simulate V1, needs the spec for it
Chase Wright: in execution APIs needs to be defined. I opened that PR this morning based on updated input from the client dev.
Chase Wright: in the issue. So…
Stefan Starflinger: That would be very important to get done, and, estimate guess. These two, I think, are especially important for, DevNet11 that we want to launch, because we've gotten complaints from
Stefan Starflinger: Layer 2, that they want these, RPC calls to work, so they can… Test their stuff.
Chase Wright: Yeah, so ETH Estimate Gas, I know I submitted PRs to multiple clients, already, and they all basically got merged, I think.
Chase Wright: So if there are more issues with East Estimate Gas, then hit me up in Discord, and we'll… we'll take a look at them.
Stefan Starflinger: Sounds good.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: Thank you.
Boma: And then, I think that's the… all for today, then we…
Boma: Still have this pending on how to cut a release.
Boma: Because I believe a release will also help in the DevNets testing, sort of.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I mean, I still… I still sit on the, let's… let's fix Amsterdam, and then let's do a release.
Boma: Yeah, but you also promised to, like, create a meta-issue on what is going… what should be in the release.
Chase Wright: But you got me there. Yes, I did, and I forgot to do that, so…
Chase Wright: I will make note. I'll do that.
Boma: Okay,
Boma: Okay, thank you. I think that's basically from the agenda. I don't know if anyone has any other thing to say or issue to…
Boma: point out.
Boma: Alright then.
Boma: That's all for today. Thank you all for joining. See you all, next two weeks, I guess.
Boma: Have a great day.
Stefan Starflinger: Thank you.
Chase Wright: Bye.
Łukasz Rozmej: Bye.